Hi everybody, welcome back to the channel
and I've just been to the store and grabbed
these limited edition Oreo space dunk
cookies and we're going to turn them
into a limited edition cookies and cream
ice cream so let's see how we do it [Music]
Yeah what are they? Well space dunk, here you
go look I'll put a bigger picture picture up
on the screen, they are cosmic cream with popping
candy. They have got pink and blue cream inside,
yep popping candy cream tastes the
same still that vanilla kind of
flavor basically just tast like... oh
you're getting it now getting some of
that popping candy come through, for a bit of
fun let's create a double color cookies and
cream rather than make it, you know, vanilla
flavored, let's make this mint flavored. So
mint double color cookies and cream ice cream.
So for this ice cream recipe we're going to use
18% fat coffee cream just because that's what
I picked up from the store so for this we're
going to need 750g of coffee cream 18% fat, 160g
of sugar, 30g of dextrose, 50g of skimmed milk
powder and 2g of your stabilizer blend if
you are going to use it. And we're going to
do two batches of this, one is going to have red
food coloring and one is going to have blue food
coloring and we're probably going to put mint in
both of them so let's get these bases mixed up.
So like I said, I'm going to make two batches
but there's no point be showing you both. In
here we've got our milk and our cream, in
here we've got our dextrose, our sugar and
our stabilizer blend we're going to stir this up
put that in there and this is our skimmed milk
powder that is also going to go into there give
this a quick stir and let's get it on the hob.
So on the hob it goes, stir this until it comes
up to 80 - 85°C which is 180°F in Fahrenheit if
you're using a stabilizer. If you're not using
a stabilizer you don't have to go that high you
just have to warm it through to dissolve
all the sugars. We're up to temperature,
now we're going to turn the
hob off take it off the heat.
We've already done our pink one in here, exactly
the same process just pink, mint extract in here,
mint extract in here. If you're going to use
extracts in ice cream, always put them in after
the heating phase has been done. If you put them
in before and you heat it up you lose a lot of
that alcohol that these are made with and you
also lose some of that flavor profile that is
linked to it as well so add your extracts
after the heating phase. If you're unsure,
once your ice cream base is completely
cooled down in the fridge then add your
extract then you get the strongest possible
flavor. Now we're going to do is make this
one blue I'm using a gel food coloring let's
make it nice and blue recommend you use gel
food colorings try and get a food coloring
that is designed to work in fat as opposed
to water um if you can't then don't worry
about it just use whatever you've got to
hand that is definitely blue let's give
you a nice overhead shot so you can see
what we're trying to achieve here so
we've got our pink and our super blue
achieve this once they're cooled down we
will come back get them churning and get
these cookies cut up and in there so while
our machine is chilling down we're going
to take some just the cookie parts not the
cream and we're going to crush it up into
a powder into here okay those ready machine
chill down let's get the first ice cream in
[Music] we're going to get that in the freezer
while we finish dishing this batch
up and get the blue one straighten
[Music] after
next day just to recap we're making
cookies and cream with the Oreo limited
space dunk turns out actually that these
are supposed to be marshmallow flavored
cream doesn't taste like that so let's get
some dished up and then we'll top it with
something
[Music]
Scoops beautifully great double color
as you can see here topped with some
marshmallow these are cookie
centers it's just a layer of
each so obviously under
here there we go under here we've got our
ice cream here and I mean me personally
whenever I put marshmallow on
something you got to flame it
surely what does it taste like
back to the mustache,
so Oreo space dunk cookies bright blue bright pink
centers popping candy I've got it going mad in my
mouth now marshmallow flavored cream doesn't
really taste like it but we can do something
about that so what we've got is we got a bright
blue and a bright pink mint cookies and cream
it's delicious just as you'd expect and the
mouthfuls with the cookie pieces in you get
that popping candy coming through Chopped with
our burnt marshmallow you can make your own you
can also just go to the store and buy this so
this was a nice fun simple one to do hope you
like the video thanks very much for watching don't
forget to like And subscribe and I'll see you next
time